alpari-forex.com 2019-02-28

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
Alpari takes the security of its clients’ personal data and the storage of confidential information
very seriously.
To prevent any loss, misuse, changes, or unauthorised access of information by third parties, we
fulfil all relevant requirements (both administrative and technical), i.e. we regularly perform
checks, tests, and other essential reviews.
Alpari respects your right to privacy. This Privacy Policy (hereinafter, "Policy") applies to
personal information that we collect through our website (www.alpari.com) as well as any other
affiliated websites and applications. This Policy does not apply to websites operated by other
organisations and other third parties. This Policy also applies to personal information that we
collect when you use our services as well as during any correspondence held with us by
telephone, email, or otherwise. This Policy aims to inform you about the type of information we
gather, who we share it with, what we use it for, how we keep it secure, and what your data
privacy rights are.
You can always contact us should you have any questions regarding your personal data. Please
contact us at dataprotection@alpari.com.
What personal information do we collect and why?
The personal information that we may collect about you falls into the following categories:
         Information that you provide voluntarily
         You can give us your personal details, contact information, and financial data etc. by
         filling in forms or by sending them to us by post, providing them over the telephone, via
         myAlpari, email, or otherwise. This includes the personal information you provide when
         you:
                 Apply for our products or services
                 Create a myAlpari account on our website
                 Subscribe to our publications or those of affiliated third parties
                 Agree to receive promotional materials from us
                 Sign up for a contest, bonus program, promotion, or survey
                 Give us feedback
         In addition to the above, certain parts of our website may ask you to provide personal
         information voluntarily (for example, we may ask you to provide your contact details in
         order to register with myAlpari, to subscribe to promotional materials and notifications
         from us, and/or to submit enquiries to us). The personal information that you are asked to
         provide, along with the reasons for which you are asked to provide it, will be made clear
         to you at the time we ask you to provide such information.
         Information that Alpari collects automatically
         When you visit our website, certain information is sent to us from your device
         automatically. In some jurisdictions, including the European Union, this information may
         be classified as personal information under applicable data protection laws.

       Specifically, the information that is shared with us automatically may include your IP
       address, device type, unique device identification numbers, browser type, approximate
       geographic location (for example, country or city/region location), and other information.
       We also receive information about how your device has interacted with our website,
       including the pages accessed and links followed.
       Collecting this information enables us to better understand the users who visit our
       website, where they come from, and which content on our website is of interest to them.
       We use this information for internal analytical purposes and to improve the quality and
       clarity of our website for our visitors.
       Some of this information may be collected using cookies. For detailed information about
       the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them, please see our Cookie
       policy.
       Disclosure of personal information
       We may disclose your personal information to the following categories of recipients:
              Our group companies, third-party service providers, and partners who provide us
               with data processing services (for example, to support the delivery of, provide
               functionality on, or help to enhance the security of our website) or who otherwise
               process personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or
               for purposes disclosed to you when we collect your personal information.
              Any competent law enforcement body, regulatory or government agency, court,
               or other third party where we believe disclosure is necessary (i) as a matter of
               applicable law or regulation, (ii) to exercise, establish, or defend our legal rights,
               or (iii) to protect your vital interests or those of any other person.
              Any other person with your consent to the disclosure of such information.
Legal basis for processing personal information
       Alpari will collect personal information from you in cases where we have your consent to
       do so, where we need the personal information to conclude a contract with you, or where
       such action is in our legitimate interests. In some cases, we may also have a legal
       obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal
       information to protect certain vital interests.
       If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to
       conclude a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you
       as to whether or not the provision of your personal information is mandatory.
       Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information for the purposes of serving our
       legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make those legitimate interests
       clear to you at the relevant time.
       If you have any questions about the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal
       information, please contact us.
Purposes for which we will use your personal information
       1. Serving you as a client

      Type of data: Identity (Name, country of residence, address, and other similar
      information), Contact details (email address, telephone number, webpage, messenger
      IDs, and similar), National identity documents (passport, identity card, residency permit,
      US residency information, and similar), Financial (bank account details, bank card
      numbers and holder name, documents confirming origin of capital, and other similar),
      Political exposure (documents and waivers), Documentation (copies of documents to
      support provided information).
      Purpose: Registering you as a new client, providing access to your trading account,
      delivering our products and services, facilitating your withdrawals, deposits, and funds
      transfer, and collecting funds that are owed to Alpari.
      Legal Basis: Conclusion of a contract with you or compliance with a legal requirement.
      2. Managing risk, money laundering prevention, and responding to regulatory
          requirements and legal claims
      Type of Data: Transactional, Financial, Identity
      Purpose: To comply with applicable laws, to detect, investigate, report, and seek to
      prevent money laundering, to respond to complaints, and to submit information to
      applicable governmental bodies in cases where it is required by law. To collect
      information where there is a legal obligation to do so for compliance and AML purposes,
      such as ‘know your client’ information, details relevant to international sanctions and
      restrictive measures, and information about criminal and political activities of the
      potential client, which may impact our ability to act.
      Legal Basis: compliance with a legal requirement.
      3. Marketing
      Type of Data: Contact information, Consent, and Correspondence.
      Purpose: Marketing activities and the provision of information and updates about
      products and services.
      Legal basis: Conclusion of the contract with you.
What are your rights?
     You have the right to obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you.
     You may request that we rectify any inaccurate information and/or complete any
      incomplete personal information. We will subsequently correct our records and notify
      any third parties to whom such personal information may have been transmitted as
      described above.
     You may request a copy of all personal information you have provided to us, after which
      we will transmit this information to another data controller of your choice.
     You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the
      marketing emails we send you.
     You may request that we stop processing your personal information. Please note that you
      may not be able to benefit from certain features of our service for which the processing of
      your personal information is necessary.

       You may withdraw your consent to the processing of your personal information at any
        time. Such withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing to which you have
        previously given consent. Please note that if you withdraw your consent, you may not be
        able to benefit from certain features of our service for which the processing of your
        personal information is necessary.
       You may request that we erase your personal information and we will comply, unless
        there is a lawful reason for not doing so.
       You reserve the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority.
What are the security measures?
        We apply appropriate technical and administrative measures to protect the personal
        information that Alpari collects and processes. The measures we use are designed to
        provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal
        information. In particular, we:
               Hold personal information in secure facilities and; where the information is held
                electronically, on secure servers.
               Use encrypted transmission links whenever we can.
               Use other safeguards such as firewalls, authentication systems (e.g., passwords),
                and access control mechanisms to prevent unauthorised access to systems and
                data.
               Regularly review our information collection, storage, and processing practices,
                including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorised access to
                systems.
               Restrict access to personal information to our employees, contractors, and agents
                who need to know such information in order to process it for us and who are
                subject to strict contractual confidentiality obligations.
International data transfers
Subject to certain conditions, we may transfer your personal information to third parties in other
countries for further processing in accordance with the purposes set out in this Policy. In certain
cases, this may include transferring data to countries which do not offer the same level of
protection as the laws of your country of residence. In such cases, we will, as required by
applicable law, ensure that your privacy rights are adequately protected by appropriate technical,
administrative, contractual, or other lawful means. These include putting data transfer
agreements in place for the transmission of personal information between our group companies,
which require all group companies to protect the personal information they process in
accordance with applicable data protection laws. We have implemented similar appropriate
safeguards with our third party service providers and partners, for which further details can be
provided upon request.
Data retention
        Your personal information will be retained for as long as it is necessary to carry out the
        purposes set out in this Policy (unless longer retention is required by law). However, we
        will not retain any of your personal information beyond this period and the retention of
        your personal information will be subject to periodic review.
Automated decision-making

       In some instances, our use of your personal information may result in automated
       decisions being taken (including profiling) that legally affect you or similarly
       significantly affect you.
       Automated decisions mean that a decision concerning you is made automatically on the
       basis of a computer determination (using software algorithms), without human oversight.
       When we make an automated decision about you, you have the right to contest the
       decision, to express your point of view, and to demand a human review of the decision.
Get in touch
       We would be happy to hear your views about our website and this Privacy Policy –
       please let us know any questions, comments or clarifications you may have at
       dataprotection@alpari.com.
